# **Eva Murphy**

213 Crooked Cedar Way, Pendleton, SC, 20670 803-944-7265 — nagy@clemson.edu

### **Professional Summary**

As an educator I have had the opportunity to work with students that have a wide range of learning abilities. This experience has taught me how to be flexible and how to adjust my teaching skills to reach every student's interest in math. I also learned how to set high expectations for every type of student by helping each of them reach their goals, and how to teach the essential concepts from college curriculum through functional and applied strategies.

My research interests include statistical modeling, spatio-temporal modeling and data fusion with a focus on environmental data. In my dissertation thesis I concentrate on the statistical modeling of the spatio-temporal variation of wind speed and wind direction. This gave me the opportunity to learn how to build flexible models for large data sets that are non-stationary and non-Gaussian. Furthermore, I use R programming language to clean large data sets, perform exploratory analysis and conduct statistical inference.

## **Professional Experience**

Clemson University, Clemson, SC 29634, 2018 - Present

Mid-Carolina High School, Prosperity, S.C., 29127, 2006-2011, 2012-2018

Wade Hampton High School, Varnville, S.C., 29944, 2011-2012

Midlands Technical College, Columbia, SC, 29202, 2016 - 2018

Piedmont Technical College, Columbia, SC, 29202, 2015 - 2020

#### **Education**

Ph.D. in Mathematical and Statistical Sciences, Clemson University, South Carolina, USA,

2018Present

M.S. in Mathematical Sciences, University of West Florida, Florida, USA, 2014-2016

Bachelor's degree in Mathematical Sciences, Babes-Bolyai University, Romania, 2002-2006

### **Presentations and Posters**

Joint of wind modeling speed and wind direction through a conditional approach presented at:

- · Joint Statistical Meeting, August 2022.
- · Climate informatics, May 2022.
- · SC-ASA Palmetto Symposium, April 2022.
- · Math For All Satellite Conference at Clemson University, February 2022.

Modeling of Wind Speed and Wind Direction presented at GSN Graduate Student Research Conference, May 2022.

Statistical framework for studying the spatio-temporal variation of wind speed and wind direction - Literature Review, presented at GSN Graduate Student Research Conference, June 2021

#### PARTICIPATIONS AND AWARDS

*Chair* of the Statistical Analyzes for Environmental Monitoring — Contributed Papers section at the Joint Statistical Meeting, August 2022.

Award: Best Talk Award at the SC-ASA Palmetto Symposium, April 2022.

*Paper review*: I participated as a reviewer for the 11th International Conference on Climate Informatics, reviewing 3 extended abstracts, March 2022.

Certificates: Completion of Clemson Thinks<sup>2</sup> Graduate Teaching Institute, Fall of 2021.

STRIVE for MORE where I was a mentor in the Near - to - Peer Mentoring Session, September 2020 and 2021.

### **Teaching Experience**

**Graduate Teacher of Record (GTR)**: my responsibilities were: to instruct Precalculus, Business Calculus I, Business Calculus II, Calculus of Single Variable, tutor students taking the mathematics classes I taught. keep online records of attendance and student performance, attend professional meetings.

**Teacher of Mathematics**: my responsibilities were: to instruct Applied Algebra, Algebra 2, Algebra 2- Honors, Algebra 3/Trigonometry, A.P. Calculus AB, Geometry, Intermediate Statistics and Probability, organize course matters and make certain the content is accurately taught, create and execute project work plans and revise as appropriate to meet changing needs and requirements, manage parent and teacher meetings on a usual basis in support of make certain that parents recognize everything regarding their child's growth, supervise and tutor students taking various mathematics classes ranging from finite math to calculus, teach study skills and test taking skills, keep online records of attendance and student performance, attend professional meetings, educational conferences, and teacher training workshops in order to maintain and

improve professional competence, perform administrative duties such as assisting in school libraries, and hall, cafeteria and parking lot monitoring.

**Adjunct Instructor of Mathematics**: my responsibilities were: to instruct Beginning Algebra, Intermediate Algebra, Analytical Geometry and Calculus I, to instruct online Probability and Statistics and Algebra, Geometry and Trigonometry I, keep online records of attendance and student performance, attend professional meetings, educations conferences, and teacher training workshops in order to maintain and improve professional competence.